<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Untitled RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>site-lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Untitled RSS Feed</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:32:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="site-lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:32:48 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Final Project Notes]]></title><description><![CDATA[
Roguelike
Turn based
Progress up the tower, each level has a different enemy to fight
Win once you reach the top of the tower (3-4 levels)
20 minutes of gameplay maximum
Game assets should have a kind of cute pixelated vibe
4 characters to choose from initially with different classes.
Each class has different abilities they can learn, up to 3?
Abilities have different attack patterns, hit different grid tiles
Wizard for example can hit from farther away, longer range attacks
Ideas:
Rogue (Lower health, higher speed)
Warrior (Higher health, lower speed)
Wizard (Magic attacks, nature theme? Vines, rose thorns etc.)
Ability to customize armour / weapon colours, maybe add a symbol on chestplate?
Could cycle through presets like star, heart, etc.
Tower with 3-4 levels
Open to the outdoors
Elegant vibe, white marble or cobblestone
Ground becomes farther away as you progress each level
Final level can see the sky?
<img alt="Environment Concept Art.png" src="environment-concept-art.png" target="_self">Turn based but on a grid, sort of pokemon mystery dungeon style
Could maybe make it so that the projectiles only move when the player moves so that you need to be strategic about it?
Each attack hits certain tiles on the grid, different patterns for each bossShould drop coins and/or items, not guaranteed drop, typical loot mechanics
Can maybe look into Pokemon games for move ideas
Fire boss (Jayda) Dragon
Bear (sun vibes?) Water boss (Jayce) Reptile?
Zebak mechanics (dont worry about this it's jayce's problem) Poison boss (Shannon) Venus fly trap?
Scorpion
Snake / reptile Can sell loot from bosses for gold coins
Use gold to buy items. Current items: Health pot
Maybe better armour / weapons? Theming / Skins
Player will be able to customize their armour colour / symbol
Advanced Computer AI
Boss could check the armour of the player and adjust accordingly Example: If using fire resistant armour, boss starts using water-based attacks
Detailed Statistics
Add timer for the run
Favourite attack
Alternate Rulesets / Modes
Newgame+
Endless mode, difficulty scales up exponentially Your game must be fully playable and implement a clear ruleset or system. If the rules aren’t common knowledge, be ready to provide your professor with reference material for the rules. Gameplay constraints like turn order/timing, collision, timing, legal plays, etc. need to be enforced. The player should be able to win or lose. Depending on genre, this may include turn‑based decision‑making (cards, board games), pathing, movement, or attack selection (tower defense, wave‑based games), enemy spawning and behaviour logic (anything besides cards), NPC interactions (RPGs). Some form of basic, rules‑based AI is required.Your project must include a GUI. It should generally be clean and functional for an average person to use. It should be accessible (with mindfulness to contrast, readable text, and keyboard friendliness) and appropriate to the type of game. Your solution must somehow demonstrate the four pillars of OOP: encapsulation, abstraction, inheritance and polymorphism. It will very likely also use a library and collections in some way. The code should generally be well‑organized (e.g. use of regions, folders, and careful naming conventions). The code body should have comment headers on all human‑generated code files/classes and meaningful comments throughout. Documentation structures that lend themselves to better development and organization, such as docstrings in Python, Javadoc in Java, or XML. Comments in C# are strongly recommended. While a style guide is not prescribed in this course, the group should agree on a style guide and adhere to it. Your finished project should include some form of user guide or tutorial. This can take many forms including a separate document, a short video, or thorough inline help in the game. This should include how to play, a guide to the controls, and an explanation of any settings/options. GitHub – or an approved alternative – needs to be used for source control and collaboration. As well, a GitHub Project board or another Kanban tool is essential and should be referred to and maintained from at least Week 4 onward As noted previously, not every optional feature will make sense for every genre of game so choose options that are appropriate. Create a more advanced computer AI that would make alternate choices rather than the default strategy; something beyond strict rule adherence so that the opponents are more responsive, and more difficult to predict and defeat Either add distinct difficulty settings, or make it so that the game becomes harder (or easier) based on time, player actions, or progress. Create planned variation in the opponents the player can encounter. Perhaps they appear and behave differently. Note that this is not a suitable optional rule to select for an RPG since having a single enemy type would be silly. Make selectable variant rules to a well‑defined game, such as alternate cards (e.g. jokers in play, wildcards) or pieces, or different board layouts. Some game styles may lend themselves well to an endless mode, or a puzzle mode. Allow several player‑selectable UI or visual themes. ]]></description><link>final-project-notes.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">🖤 School/Object Oriented Programming/Final Project Notes.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:32:02 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="." length="0" type="false"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;.&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>